A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, RG 2, 1958-1970 FA400
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, RG 2, 1958-1970
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA400
7.04 Cubic Feet 704 35mm microfilm reels
Scope and Contents note
Rockefeller Foundation general correspondence:
Correspondence of The Rockefeller Foundation consists principally of material not directly connected with an institutional grant. It includes inter-office memoranda; correspondence between field officers and the home office; extracts from officers' diaries; forms and other material relating to fellowships; casual requests for information, employment, or aid; printed matter; and letters of abuse received by the Foundation. As such, the General Correspondence provides insight into the day-to-day workings of the Foundation.
Programs other than public health are not amply represented in the early portion of the General Correspondence. Material on the Division of Humanities and the Division of Social Sciences is especially scanty before 1935. After 1940, the volume of this material increases steadily. Indeed, the General Correspondence files as a whole are relatively compact up to 1940; after 1941, they expand enormously.
Some of the most important features and subjects of these files are as follows:
100: STAFF COMMUNICATIONS AND INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS
This designation applies to two distinct types of documents.
(1) STAFF COMMUNICATIONS. Much of the material under this heading consists of correspondence between or regarding staff officers (eg. a field officer and a member of the home office staff), or gives details of employment and assignment of the field officer. Thus this file is in the nature of a supplement of the Foundation's personnel records. Correspondence between retirees and active staff members is often also filed under this designation, under the names of the individuals. One will also find here inter-office correspondence from the New York headquarters. Of special interest in this connection are the memos of Raymond B. Fosdick (President of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1936-1948), which usually consist of several folders for each year indicated. Some correspondence with trustees, especially Thomas B. Debevoise, may also be found here.
(2) INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS. Correspondence between The Rockefeller Foundation and the League of Nations (especially with Arthur Sweetser) lodges under this heading and persists into the 1940s. After the establishment of the United Nations Organization in 1944/5, documentation of the Foundation's cooperation with various U.N. efforts is to be found. Of special interest are the files regarding Selskar M. Gunn and Warren Weaver's service with UNRRA (1944-1946) and John Marshall's presence as an observer at the earliest organizational meetings of UNESCO (1946-1947).
200: THE UNITED STATES (201-258: Individual States and Territories)
The largest concentration of material is to be found under this designation. It is also the most miscellaneous in character. Correspondence ranges from communications with Federal agencies and departments, to letters of advice, records of interviews, appeals for aid, employment inquiries, and crank mail.
The vast bulk of these files dating between 1927 and 1939 relates to the work of the International Health Division, supplementing material previously processed as RG 5. This includes material on grants to state boards of health, training grants for public health personnel at stations in Ohio or Mississippi, and advice on administrative matters. Following the practice of the IHD, most of these earlier files were arranged under an individual state heading rather than under that of the nation as a whole. By 1935 most of the IHD activities had declined as funding became available to the states through the Federal government for this purpose. Correspondence with the individual state agencies shrank accordingly. The advisory functions of the IHD thereafter took place mainly in the form of pooling information (and occasionally personnel) with the U.S. Public Health Service.
Those states files which remain sizeable after 1935 (such as 216: Illinois-University of Chicago, and 248: Tennessee: TVA) do not relate primarily to IHD activities. In 1951, the use of state numbers in filing was almost totally abandoned.
200: UNITED STATES PUBLIC HEALTH SERVICE
During World War II, the Foundation maintained close ties with USPHS, as reflected in the large file of correspondence between Foundation officers and various USPHS officials. This file refers particularly to the Foundation's effort to provide yellow fever vaccine to the Armed Forces. Also of interest for this period is a set of weekly reports on the incidence of virulent disease (plague, smallpox, etc.) around the world.
200E: FELLOWSHIPS
The earlier portion of material so designated (through 1935) is taken up with grants for training public health personnel as requested by various state boards of health. It thus amplifies the documentation of IHD activities noted above. This material includes both declinations as well as acceptances.
Similar material through the 1930s is to be found under 200S: Social Science Research Council, consisting mostly of application forms and correspondence concerning potential SSRC grantees.
For the years 1945-46, an extensive file of Postwar Fellowships follows the regular fellowship file in the General Correspondence. While the character of Foundation support of these Fellows is unclear, the advisory function of Foundation officers in their selection and placement is amply documented here.
300-833: INDIVIDUAL NATIONAL FILES
The files under this heading include administrative and budgetary material for field offices, reports of interviews with potential grantees, governmental and educational figures, diary extracts (usually travel notes, sometimes quite extensive), and miscellaneous correspondence with private and public scientific or cultural institutions and individuals. The majority of this material (especially before 1935) continues the records of the IHD in its international program (see RG 5), and deals primarily with public health programs and medical training. After 1935, the subject matter in the files becomes more diversified.
Scattered throughout these series are observations by Foundation officers on the political and social climate around the world. The Rockefeller Foundation maintained political neutrality regarding the internal affairs of host countries, and cooperated closely with governmental ministries and state-controlled universities -- especially in the areas of public health and the social sciences. Nevertheless, a close watch was kept on developments affecting intellectual freedom and the general climate of cooperation which the Foundation saw as the main prerequisite for performing or sponsoring significant work. This is reflected in the General Correspondence files, where one may find contemporary eyewitness reports and informed outside opinions on such phenomena of this century as the development of Fascism in Europe, the growth of Communism in eastern Europe and China, and the rise or fall of various dictatorships in Latin America.
Large quantities of material may be found under the following headings:
300: South America 315: Cuba 400: Great Britain 427: Canada 437: Jamaica 464: India (including 464.1: Mysore and 464.5: Travancore, through 1944) 500: France 601: China 700: Europe
The bulk of these files indicates either high levels of Foundation activity or the presence of a field office in the country concerned, and thus an "Administration" file will be found here as well as material filed alphabetically or under a program letter. Special features include the 1945-46, 500E file (France-Government Fellowships), which consist of material similar to that described under 200E for the same period. Under 700, one will also find material on the Paris Field Office supplementing that processed separately as RG 6.1.
SPECIAL TOPIC: REFUGEE SCHOLARS, 1933-1946
The General Correspondence contains a mass of material on the plight of European scholars deprived of means or work by the rise of Fascism. This material is similar and supplementary to that found in RG 1 under the same heading. Most of the material in the General Correspondence bearing on this topic may be found as listed below:
717: Germany--Refugee Scholars, 1933-1939 789: Poland-----Refugee Scholars, 1936-1939 200: U.S.---------Refugee Scholars, 1940-1945
These files generally fall into two parts:
(1) A chronological file entitled "Exiled Scholars" which consists of officer's correspondence, diary extracts, lists of exiled academics compiled from various sources, correspondence with various committees and institutions engaged in placing these scholars, and copies of the minutes of those committees with which The Rockefeller Foundation cooperated most closely.
(2) An alphabetical file of correspondence with or concerning individual scholars whose placement the Foundation sponsored or financed in part.
(3) Much material filed under 700: Europe and individual European country numbers (including 400: Great Britain, and 805: Turkey) during the period 1933-1945 also deals with this topic.
Arrangement note
The original filing system has been retained. As with RG 1 (Project Files), this filing system is geographic-numeric; i.e., each country, state, and/or geographic region has been assigned a specific number that is used as the basic document classifier. Letters following a number refer to the project area to which the document refers. An individual or institution is in most instances used as the secondary classifier. This secondary classifier may denote either the institution or the individual from which the correspondence derived, or the subject of the correspondence itself. The principal difference in organization between the RG 1 and RG 2 is that General Correspondence is also organized in annual blocks, while individual project files may cover a number of years.
Important irregularities in the original filing order are noted below:
(1) 100 files are strictly alphabetical until 1941; after 1941, miscellaneous A-Z files are maintained containing small amounts of material on individuals. These immediately follow the main 100 file.
(2) Correspondence with various state boards of public health precede the alphabetical file for each state or territory of the United States (201-258).
(3) Administration files for RF field offices precede the alphabetical file for the country in which they were established.
Post-1951 General Correspondence are processed as annual blocks of material and added to this register when work on the material for each year is completed.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Archival records have been reformatted to microfilm. User copies are open for research.
Europe; Dictatorship -- Latin America; Fascism -- Europe; Philanthropy; Fascism; Communism -- Europe, Eastern; Communism; Dictatorship; Cuba; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Canada; China; Charities; Viruses -- Research; Yellow fever; Yellow fever -- Vaccination; Philanthropy -- United States; Refugees; Social sciences; South America; United States; Public health; Medical research; Refugee Scholars -- Germany; Medical sciences; Life sciences; Medical education; India; Jamaica; Great Britain; Humanities; Arts; France; Refugee Scholars -- United States; Refugee Scholars -- World War II; Refugee Scholars -- Poland; Unesco; United Nations
- General Correspondence, 1958
  Appraisal note
  The archival material has been reformatted and the original records are no longer available. User copies of the microfilm are available for access.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
  - International, 1958/100
    - Aitken, Thomas H. G. (Reel 1, Frame 1)
    - Allen, LeRoy R. (Reel 1, Frame 52)
    - Anderson, Charles R. (Reel 1, Frame 117)
    - Anderson, Richmond K. (Reel 1, Frame 176)
    - Arnold, Virginia (Reel 1, Frame 203)
    - Baird, Guy B. (Reel 1, Frame 257)
    - Balfour, Marshall C. (Reel 1, Frame 268)
    - Belknap, Chauncey (Reel 1, Frame 279)
    - Borlaug, Norman E. (Reel 1, Frame 281)
    - Braga, Ernani (Reel 1, Frame 135)
    - Buchanan, Norman S. (Reel 1, Frame 375)
    - Bugher, John C. (Reel 1, Frame 412)
    - Burden, Robert P. (Reel 1, Frame 434)
    - Causey, Ottis R. (Reel 1, Frame 439)
    - Chandler, Robert F., Jr. (Reel 1, Frame 472)
    - Cobb, William C. (Reel 1, Frame 513)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom (B-S) (Reel 1, Frame 541)
    - Crowder, Loy V. (Reel 1, Frame 923)
    - Cummings, Ralph W. (Reel 1, Frame 994)
    - DeVinney, Leland C. (Reel 1, Frame 1049)
    - Diplomatic Services (A-K) (Reel 1, Frame 1052)
    - Diplomatic Services (L-Y) (Reel 2, Frame 1)
    - Downs, Wilbur G. (Reel 2, Frame 105)
    - Fahs, Charles Burton (Reel 2, Frame 166)
    - Gibler, John W. (Reel 2, Frame 177)
    - Gilpatric, Chadbourne (Reel 2, Frame 197)
    - Grant, John B. (Reel 2, Frame 214)
    - Grant, Ulysses J. (Reel 2, Frame 276)
    - Gregg, Alan (Reel 2, Frame 305)
    - Gregg, Lucien A. (Reel 2, Frame 325)
    - Halpin, James E. (Reel 2, Frame 389)
    - Harrar, J. George (Reel 2, Frame 416)
    - Harrison, John P. (Reel 2, Frame 554)
    - Harwood, Roland E. (Reel 2, Frame 574)
    - Hatheway, William H. (Reel 2, Frame 592)
    - Hayes, Guy S. (Reel 2, Frame 600)
    - Hill, Rolla B. (Reel 2, Frame 705)
    - International (A-B) (Reel 2, Frame 709)
    - International (C) (Reel 2, Frame 766)
    - International (F-W) (Reel 2, Frame 910)
    - Janney, John H. (Reel 2, Frame 1010)
    - Jennings, Peter R. (Reel 2, Frame 1014)
    - Johnson, Harald N. (Reel 2, Frame 1060)
    - Kerr, J. Austin (Reel 3, Frame 1)
    - Kimball, Lindsley F. (Reel 3, Frame 105)
    - Knipe, Frederick W. (Reel 3, Frame 109)
    - Kokernot, Robert H. (Reel 3, Frame 138)
    - Lee, Ivy (Reel 3, Frame 165)
    - Maier, John (Reel 3, Frame 182)
    - Marshall, John (Reel 3, Frame 268)
    - McCune, Donald L. (Reel 3, Frame 338)
    - McKelvey, John J., Jr. (Reel 3, Frame 409)
    - Miller, Harry Milton, Jr. (Reel 3, Frame 430)
    - Morison, Robert S. (Reel 3, Frame 463)
    - Moseman, Albert H. (Reel 3, Frame 538)
    - Niederhauser, John S. (Reel 3, Frame 607)
    - Parker, Dorothy (Reel 3, Frame 661)
    - Perry, Jesse P. (Reel 3, Frame 750)
    - Peterson, Osler L. (Reel 3, Frame 859)
    - Pomerat, Gerard R. (Reel 3, Frame 931)
    - Rachie, Kenneth O. (Reel 3, Frame 944)
    - Roberts, Lewis M. (Reel 3, Frame 1013)
    - Rupert, Joseph A. (Reel 3, Frame 1108)
    - Ruppel, Robert F. (Reel 3, Frame 1134)
    - Rusk, Dean (Reel 4, Frame 1)
    - Russell, Paul F. (January-March) (Reel 4, Frame 102)
    - Russell, Paul F. (April-December) (Reel 4, Frame 254)
    - Skiles, Robert L. (Reel 4, Frame 409)
    - Smith, Donald L. (Reel 4, Frame 507)
    - Smithburn, Kenneth C. (Reel 4, Frame 563)
    - Sprague, Ernest W. (Reel 4, Frame 616)
    - Stakman, Elvin C. (January-July) (Reel 4, Frame 697)
    - Stakman, Elvin C. (August-December) (Reel 4, Frame 813)
    - Stakman, Elvin C., Award (Reel 4, Frame 867)
    - Taylor, Richard M. (Reel 4, Frame 871)
    - Tennant, Mary Elizabeth (Reel 4, Frame 911)
    - Timothy, David H. (Reel 4, Frame 918)
    - Trapido, Harold (Reel 4, Frame 978)
    - United Nations, Food and Agriculture Organization (A-W) (Reel 4, Frame 1075)
    - United Nations, World Health Organization (A-W) (Reel 5, Frame 1)
    - United Nations (A-T) (Reel 5, Frame 265)
    - United Nations Economic and Social Council (Phillips, Christopher H.) (Reel 5, Frame 396)
    - United Nations Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization (A-L) (Reel 5, Frame 403)
    - United Nations Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization (M-Y) (Reel 5, Frame 614)
    - United Nations Refugee Fund (Reel 5, Frame 777)
    - Watson, Robert B. (Reel 5, Frame 780)
    - Waugh, Robert K. (Reel 5, Frame 965)
    - Weaver, Warren (Reel 5, Frame 1066)
    - Webb, Hubert E. (Reel 5, Frame 1147)
    - Weir, John M. (Reel 6, Frame 1)
    - Wellhausen, Edwin J. (Reel 6, Folder 77)
    - Wernimont, Kenneth (Reel 6, Frame 112)
    - Work, Telford H. (Reel 6, Frame 149)
    - A-B (Reel 6, Frame 380)
    - Ca-Ch (Reel 6, Frame 464)
    - Cl-Co (Reel 6, Frame 600)
    - D-E (Reel 6, Frame 730)
    - F-G (Reel 6, Frame 820)
    - H (Reel 6, Frame 906)
    - I-L (Reel 6, Frame 978)
    - M-N (Reel 7, Frame 1)
    - O-P (Reel 7, Frame 178)
    - R (Reel 7, Frame 287)
    - S (Reel 7, Frame 461)
    - T (Reel 7, Frame 529)
    - V-Y (Reel 7, Frame 636)
    - International - Nursing, 1958/100.C
      Nursing
      - 100C (Reel 7, Frame 821)
    - International - Fellowships, 1958/100.E
      Fellowships
      - 100E (Reel 7, Frame 828)
    - International - Malaria, 1958/100.I
      Malaria
      - 100I (Reel 7, Frame 874)
    - International - Yellow Fever, 1958/100.O
      Yellow fever
      - 100O (Reel 7, Frame 883)
    - International - Social Sciences, 1958/100.S
      Social sciences
      - Diplomacy (University Teaching) (Reel 7, Frame 892)
      - Foreign Affairs (Books) (Reel 7, Frame 919)
    - International - Virus Studies, 1958/100.V
      Virology
      - United Nations (World Health Organization) (Reel 7, Frame 1030)
  - United States, 1958/200
    United States
    - Aa-Af (Reel 7, Frame 1090)
    - Ag-Al (Reel 8, Frame 1)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (G-W) (Reel 8, Frame 121)
    - American Council on Education (A-R) (Reel 8, Frame 158)
    - American Council (E-V) (Reel 8, Frame 283)
    - American (A-C) (Reel 8, Frame 377)
    - American (D-G) (Reel 8, Frame 532)
    - American (H-L) (Reel 8, Folder 696)
    - American (M) (Reel 8, Frame 859)
    - American (N-P) (Reel 8, Frame 1034)
    - American (R-W) (Reel 9, Frame 1)
    - Am-Ar (Reel 9, Frame 102)
    - Asia (F-S) (Reel 9, Frame 177)
    - Association (A-T) (Reel 9, Frame 365)
    - As-Ay (Reel 9, Frame 560)
    - Ba-Be (Reel 9, Frame 685)
    - Bio-Sciences Information Exchange (Reel 9, Frame 874)
    - Bi-Bo (Reel 10, Frame 1)
    - Brookings Institution (A-W) (Reel 10, Frame 178)
    - Br (Reel 10, Frame 370)
    - Bu-By (Reel 10, Frame 534)
    - Carnegie (C-I) (Reel 10, Frame 647)
    - Ca (Reel 10, Frame 824)
    - Ce-Ci (Reel 10, Frame 987)
    - Cl (Reel 10, Frame 1107)
    - Columbia University (B-F) (Reel 11, Frame 1)
    - Columbia University (G-W) (Reel 11, Frame 100)
    - Coc-Col (Reel 11, Frame 281)
    - Com-Coo (Reel 11, Frame 425)
    - Council (A-W) (Reel 11, Frame 543)
    - Cor-Cox (Reel 11, Frame 686)
    - Cr-Cu (Reel 11, Frame 907)
    - Da (Reel 11, Frame 956)
    - De-Dr (Reel 11, Frame 1084)
    - Duke University (Commonwealth Studies Center) (Reel 12, Frame 1)
    - Duke University (C-W) (Reel 12, Frame 209)
    - Du-Dw (Reel 12, Frame 257)
    - E (Reel 12, Frame 265)
    - Fa-Fl (Reel 12, Frame 406)
    - Ford Foundation (A-L) (Reel 12, Frame 596)
    - Ford Foundation (M-W) (Reel 12, Frame 713)
    - Fo-Fr (Reel 12, Frame 869)
    - Fulbright Program (E-H) (Reel 13, Frame 1)
    - Fu (Reel 13, Frame 147)
    - Ga-Ge (Reel 13, Frame 175)
    - Gi-Go (Reel 13, Frame 360)
    - Gr-Gu (Reel 13, Frame 450)
    - Harvard University (B-E) (Reel 13, Frame 585)
    - Harvard University (F-L) (Reel 13, Frame 724)
    - Harvard University (M-R) (Reel 13, Frame 873)
    - Harvard University (School of Public Health) (Reel 13, Frame 1040)
    - Harvard University (S-W) (Reel 14, Frame 1)
    - Ha (Reel 14, Frame 82)
    - He (Reel 14, Frame 196)
    - Hi (Reel 14, Frame 397)
    - Ho-Hu (Reel 14, Frame 524)
    - Indiana University (A-Y) (Reel 14, Frame 658)
    - Institute for International Order (Reel 14, Frame 825)
    - Institute (A-P) (Reel 14, Frame 987)
    - International (B-S) (Reel 15, Frame 1)
    - I (Reel 15, Frame 90)
    - Ja-Je (Reel 15, Frame 263)
    - Johns Hopkins University (B-W) (Reel 15, Frame 395)
    - Jo-Ju (Reel 15, Frame 571)
    - K (Reel 15, Frame 764)
    - Library of Congress (B-W) (Reel 15, Frame 931)
    - La-Li (Reel 16, Frame 1)
    - Lo-Lu (Reel 16, Frame 191)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (B-C) (Reel 16, Frame 225)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (D-Z) (Reel 16, Frame 430)
    - Ma-Mc (Reel 16, Frame 525)
    - Me (Reel 16, Frame 689)
    - Mi (Reel 16, Frame 779)
    - Mo-My (Reel 16, Frame 1016)
    - National (A-B) (Reel 17, Frame 1)
    - National (C-D) (Reel 17, Frame 142)
    - National (E-F) (Reel 17, Frame 280)
    - National (G-L) (Reel 17, Frame 391)
    - National (M-R) (Reel 17, Frame 551)
    - National (S-W) (Reel 17, Frame 671)
    - Na (Reel 17, Frame 874)
    - New York (A-P) (Reel 17, Frame 923)
    - New York University (A-Z) (Reel 18, Frame 1)
    - New York (S-Z) (Reel 18, Frame 163)
    - Ne (Reel 18, Frame 355)
    - No-Nu (Reel 18, Frame 573)
    - Oa-Ob (Reel 18, Frame 782)
    - Oc-Oh (Reel 18, Frame 969)
    - Ok-Ox (Reel 18, Frame 1072)
    - Pan American Sanitary Bureau (B-L) (Reel 19, Frame 1)
    - Pan American Sanitary Bureau (M-W) (Reel 19, Frame 165)
    - Pan American Union (C-P) (Reel 19, Frame 516)
    - Pa-Pe (Reel 19, Frame 846)
    - Ph-Po (Reel 19, Frame 1046)
    - Princeton University (A-L) (Reel 20, Frame 1)
    - Princeton University (M-W) (Reel 20, Frame 154)
    - Pr-Pu (Reel 20, Frame 229)
    - Q (Reel 20, Frame 368)
    - Ra (Reel 20, Frame 380)
    - Re-Ri (Reel 20, Frame 550)
    - Rockefeller (Reel 20, Frame 745)
    - Ro (Reel 20, Frame 903)
    - Ru (Reel 20, Frame 1046)
    - Sa (Reel 21, Frame 1)
    - Sc (Reel 21, Frame 168)
    - Se-Si (Reel 21, Frame 261)
    - Slavic Studies (Joint Committee) (Reel 21, Frame 386)
    - Sl-Sr (Reel 21, Frame 575)
    - Stanford (R-U) (Reel 21, Frame 731)
    - St-Sy (Reel 21, Frame 894)
    - Ta-To (Reel 21, Frame 1049)
    - Tr-Tw (Reel 22, Frame 1)
    - United States, Agriculture (A-P) (Reel 22, Frame 156)
    - United States, Agriculture (R-Z) (Reel 22, Frame 301)
    - United States (A-F) (Reel 22, Frame 430)
    - United States, International Cooperation Administration (A-G) (Reel 22, Frame 571)
    - United States, International Cooperation Administration (H) (Reel 22, Frame 744)
    - United States, International Cooperation Administration (J-S) (Reel 22, Frame 969)
    - United States, International Cooperation Administration (T-Y) (Reel 23, Frame 1)
    - United States (H-I) (Reel 23, Frame 211)
    - United States (J-N) (Reel 23, Frame 334)
    - United States, Senate (C-M) (Reel 23, Frame 454)
    - United States, State (A-H) (Reel 23, Frame 536)
    - United States (I-Y) (Reel 23, Frame 655)
    - United States (P-T) (Reel 23, Frame 795)
    - United States Book Exchange (Reel 23, Frame 1006)
    - United States Civil Administration of the Ryukyus (Bartz, Carl F., Jr.) (Reel 23, Frame 1008)
    - United States Educational Foundation in India (Reddick, Olive I.) (Reel 23, Frame 1011)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Pakistan (Reel 23, Frame 1018)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Thailand (Reel 23, Frame 1031)
    - United States Information Agency (A-W) (Reel 23, Frame 1033)
    - United States Steel Corporation (Reel 23, Frame 1126)
    - United States Steel Foundation (Reel 23, Frame 1128)
    - University (A-B) (Reel 24, Frame 1)